<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: bash | Devin Wadsworth]]></title>
  <link href="http://devinwadsworth.com/blog/categories/bash/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://devinwadsworth.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-05T17:07:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://devinwadsworth.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Devin Wadsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Boot]]></title>
    <link href="http://devinwadsworth.com/blog/2015/03/22/first-boot/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-22T18:23:50-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://devinwadsworth.com/blog/2015/03/22/first-boot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Switching to a new development machine is often a great opportunity to start fresh and explore new tools. That said, there&rsquo;s a core set of applications and associated preferences that I always take with me.</p>

<p>I appreciate the philosophy of sensible defaults found in Rails and similar frameworks. Context switching between multiple codebases is made easier through the widely accepted &ldquo;best practices&rdquo; that are codified in the underlying framework.</p>

<p>Sensible defaults guide you in the right direction; doing things the hard way can sometimes be avoided by embracing defaults. When the need to change a default setting presents itself, often the best solution is to change approach to better utilize the capabilities of the framework, thereby avoiding another re-invented wheel. Of course, sometimes you really do need to change settings. If the use case is wide enough to warrant it, a new default will hopefully be adopted in a future release of the framework.</p>

<p>I see similar benefits to embracing sensible defaults in the OS. Because of Apple&rsquo;s prevalence within the developer community, many development workstations already work similarly. When I set up a new Macbook I don&rsquo;t use migration assistant. Instead, I document where I&rsquo;ve deviated from the system defaults on my old computer and apply those changes on the new machine. I migrate application level preferences with <a href="https://github.com/lra/mackup">Mackup</a>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve documented my approach to setting up OS X environments for development the from the last time I switched MacBooks a few months ago: <a href="https://github.com/daymun/firstboot">github.com/daymun/firstboot</a>.</p>

<p>Feel free to fork firstboot and customize it to your liking. Please send a pull request if you discover a default that&rsquo;s not sensible!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Multiple Accounts with Harvest for Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://devinwadsworth.com/blog/2012/10/03/using-multiple-accounts-with-harvest-for-mac/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T21:52:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://devinwadsworth.com/blog/2012/10/03/using-multiple-accounts-with-harvest-for-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I need to track time on two different <a href="http://www.getharvest.com/">Harvest</a> accounts. Harvest for Mac only allows for one account, so I made a bash script to switch between multiple .plist files.</p>

<p>Save a .plist configuration under account_name:
<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>harvest new account_name</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></p>

<p>Launch with a specific .plist:
<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>harvest account_name</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></p>

<p>Check it out, there&rsquo;s more info in the readme: <a href="https://github.com/daymun/harvest-switcher">github.com/daymun/harvest-switcher</a></p>

<p>Haven&rsquo;t used Harvest? Feel free to use my <a href="http://try.hrv.st/6s5g?b">referral link</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
