<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ubuntu | Devin Wadsworth]]></title>
  <link href="http://devinwadsworth.com/blog/categories/ubuntu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://devinwadsworth.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-26T22:49:20-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://devinwadsworth.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Devin Wadsworth]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hosting Octopress on a Unix Box]]></title>
    <link href="http://devinwadsworth.com/blog/2012/06/02/hosting-octopress-on-a-unix-box/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-02T19:41:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://devinwadsworth.com/blog/2012/06/02/hosting-octopress-on-a-unix-box</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished setting up Octopress on GitHub Pages today and wanted to publish it at my personal url. Initially, I planned to <a href="https://github.com/blog/315-cname-support-for-github-pages">CNAME my domain to GitHub</a>, but apparently that feature is only available for paid accounts.</p>

<p>If you already have a paid personal GitHub account for other reasons, by all means use that. I&rsquo;ve been hosting a few other sites an an <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/devinwadsworth/3485096700/">Ubuntu based Apache server</a> for the past few years, so I decided to use that instead. Here&rsquo;s how I did it.</p>

<p>First, I set up my Ubuntu box as a git remote. There are a few different ways to do this, but I opted for the method employed by GitHub (single git user for all repositories) because I wanted to be able to host some other repositories as well. Check out this guide for some pointers on how to do this: <a href="http://www.corvidworks.com/articles/self-hosted-remote-git-repositories">http://www.corvidworks.com/articles/self-hosted-remote-git-repositories</a></p>

<p>Second, I updated my local configuration to push to this new remote. Since everything was already set up to deploy to my personal GitHub page, this was simply a matter of editing _deploy/.git/config to point to my new repository URL. I also changed the name of the new remote and <a href="https://github.com/daymun/devinwadsworth.com/commit/7a67baf7f6bc915c4c14a8258f2faa1a2de89983">updated the deploy rake task to print different info</a>, but this is an optional step.</p>

<p>Finally, I cloned the repository to my Apache document root and made a quick post-receive git hook.</p>

<p>Now I can run <code>rake deploy</code> and the site gets updated on my basement server.</p>

<p>BOOM!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
